<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>/</id>
  <title>pmercs</title>
  <subtitle><![CDATA[Powered by Cecil.]]></subtitle>
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2022-03-13T19:53:53+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>pmercs</name>
    <uri>/</uri>
  </author>
  <entry xml:lang="en">
    <id>/blog/peru-s-worst-ecological-disaster-slams-small-scale-fishing/</id>
    <title>Peru’s ‘worst ecological disaster’ slams small-scale fishing</title>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>CIUDAD PACHACUTEC, Perú (AP) — Walter de la Cruz scrambled down a large sand dune in the fog to reach a rock overlooking the Pacific Ocean, where he has fished for three decades. He cast a hook into the waters off Peru’s coast several times, with no luck. One attempt yielded a piece of plastic stained with oil.</p>
<p>De la Cruz, 60, is one of more than 2,500 fishermen whose livelihoods have been cast into doubt as a result of a large crude-oil spill at the Spanish-owned Repsol oil refinery on Jan. 15.</p>
<p>“We are desperate,” he said, counting on his fingers the debts that overwhelm him, including a bank loan, bills for water, electricity, gas, and school supplies for his two grandchildren.</p>
<p>Peru has characterized the spill of 11,900 barrels in front of a Repsol refinery as its “worst ecological disaster.” A report by United Nations experts estimates it involved about 2,100 tons of crude, well above the 700 tons the International Tanker Owners Pollution Federation Limited considers the threshold for a large spill — and an unprecedented amount for the type of crude that leaked. The oil was extracted from Buzios, the world’s largest deep water oil field and the most productive in Brazil.</p>
<p>Peru — which has a vast informal economy — does not have exact data on the number of fishermen affected, or of the people on the docks and ports who depend on the fishing industry, including restaurants, food vendors, and those who rent sun umbrellas or boats.</p>
<p>One thing is for sure: The affected artisanal fishermen are among the most economically vulnerable in Peru, harvesting small amounts of fish very close to the coast, sometimes from small boats and sometimes from the shore, said Juan Carlos Sueiro, an expert on the economics of fishing with the international conservation group Oceana.</p>
<p>“They are on the poverty line. Their income varies from day to day,” he said.</p>
<p>De la Cruz said he knew immediately that the oil spreading over more than 106 square kilometers (41 square miles) — an area larger than the city of Paris — would halt for the first time the activity carried out for centuries on Peru’s Pacific coast.</p>
<p>“I saw the fruits of my livelihood destroyed,” he said. “It’s like if you have a store and someone comes and sets it on fire.”</p>
<p>Shortly after the spill, the government announced that it was looking into giving financial aid to those affected. Authorities took three weeks to come up with a list of 2,500 fishermen whom they would help. Two weeks after that, the government said it would now be Repsol who would give as much as $799 to each of the 5,600 people affected to compensate them for the income they’ve lost because of the spill. The Presidency of the Council of Ministers did not respond to a question from The Associated Press about whether the aid promise was still valid.</p>
<p>Many fishermen here don’t have a certificate or papers to prove it is their livelihood. De la Cruz doesn’t. But he knows that he has been coming here with a basket to be filled on his back for 30 years. He normally sells or trades the fish with the owners of restaurants or local homemakers, and take some home to his wife to prepare in dishes that can be sold to neighbors.</p>
<p>De la Cruz said he felt “broken” when he saw his work space swarmed by journalists reporting on the oil spill. He wanted to tell them and the authorities what he felt, so he took a blue ink marker and wrote on a piece of cardboard, “Fishermen we need help please.”</p>
<p>Peruvian President Pedro Castillo visited the area, passed by De la Cruz, and promised to help. After looking at the puddles of oil, he’d shaken his head and said: “This can’t be.”</p>
<p>On another beach, Castillo had picked up oil-soaked sand and acknowledged the impact of the spill. “What is the use of giving nets if they no longer have a place to fish?” he said.</p>
<p>But those presidential words, which ignited De la Cruz’s hopes, have not borne fruit. More than a month after that visit, state aid does not exist.</p>
<p>“The days pass and we don’t receive anything,” he said.</p>
<p>The fishermen have protested with their empty nets in front of the Repsol refinery and blocked roads, but they still have no answers to key questions such as: Who caused the oil spill? And how long before they can return to fishing?</p>
<p>Repsol, a Spanish company, has said huge waves created by a volcanic eruption in Tonga caused the spill and that the fault lies with the Mare Doricum oil tanker. In response, the company that owns the tanker has asked that Repsol not disseminate “incorrect or misleading” information as the investigation continues.</p>
<p>Edward Málaga, a microbiologist and legislator from the centrist Morado party who has toured the polluted area and spoken with Peru’s government and Repsol officials, said political instability is causing paralysis and disorder in Castillo’s government and hindering a response.</p>
<p>Since the ecological disaster in mid-January, there have been three Cabinet shuffles and three different environment ministers. One of them was an inexperienced schoolteacher from the ruling party who barely lasted a week.</p>
<p>“You talk to an official and the following week there is another one who starts everything from scratch,” Málaga said. He said the four ministries and more than 30 associated bodies involved do not work in a coordinated manner.</p>
<p>“There is no webpage where you can go to see the work of each sector, day after day, how many fauna have been rescued, how many animals have been reported dead, how much has been cleaned,” he said.</p>
<p>So far Repsol has given out one or two cards — worth $135 each — to those affected to exchange for food at a supermarket. This is not enough to feed them, so the fishermen have organized community lunches with food donated by the Catholic Church and other organizations. In these meetings, the lack of financial aid is the recurring theme.</p>
<p>Ady Chinchay, a lawyer and researcher in environmental law, said fishermen can request compensation for loss of earnings in a civil court but there would be challenges.</p>
<p>“The judge is going to grant compensation based on the evidence” the fishermen present about their income, said Chinchay. For many of those affected by the spill, this will be almost impossible to do because they do not issue receipts when they sell their seafood.</p>
<p>This is the case with De la Cruz, who has never issued a bill of sale in 30 years.</p>
<p>“Imagine the desperation in my home,” he said. His wife sells empanadas to try to pay off debts but she no longer buys anti-inflammatories for the arthritis in her hands.</p>
<p>“Yesterday, we were just barely able to pay for natural gas,” he said.</p>]]>
    </content>
    <link href="/blog/peru-s-worst-ecological-disaster-slams-small-scale-fishing/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <published>2022-03-13T19:53:53+01:00</published>
    <updated>2022-03-13T19:53:53+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:lang="en">
    <id>/blog/biden-was-right-warmongering-putin-starts-new-world-war-and-republicans-cheer-him-on/</id>
    <title>BIDEN WAS RIGHT! Warmongering Putin Starts New World War and Republicans Cheer Him On</title>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><a href="https://apnews.com/article/russia-ukraine-putin-attack-a05e7c4563ac94b963134bba83187d46">https://apnews.com/article/russia-ukraine-putin-attack-a05e7c4563ac94b963134bba83187d46</a></p>
<!--StartFragment-->
<p>KYIV, Ukraine (AP) — Russian troops launched a wide-ranging attack on Ukraine on Thursday, as President Vladimir Putin cast aside international condemnation and sanctions and warned other countries that any attempt to interfere would lead to “consequences you have never seen.”</p>
<p>Ukrainian border guards released footage of what they said were Russian military vehicles moving in, and big explosions were heard in the capital Kyiv, Kharkiv in the east and Odesa in the west. As the Russian military claimed to have wiped out Ukraine’s entire air defenses in a matter of hours, Ukrainians fled some cities and European authorities declared Ukrainian air space an active conflict zone.</p>
<p>World leaders decried the start of a long-anticipated invasion with far-reaching consequences, as global financial markets plunged and oil prices soared. Russia’s actions could cause massive casualties, topple Ukraine’s democratically elected government and upend geopolitics and Europe’s post-Cold War security balance.</p>
<p>Governments from the U.S. to Asia and Europe readied new sanctions after weeks of failed efforts for a diplomatic solution — but global powers have said they will not intervene militarily to defend Ukraine.</p>
<p>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskyy cut diplomatic ties with Moscow and declared martial law, saying Russia has targeted Ukraine’s military infrastructure. Ukrainians who had long braced for the prospect of an assault were urged to stay home and not to panic even as Ukrainian authorities reported artillery barrages and airstrikes on targets around the country.</p>
<p>After weeks of denying plans to invade, Putin justified his actions in an overnight televised address, asserting that the attack was needed to protect civilians in eastern Ukraine — a false claim the U.S. had predicted he would make as a pretext for an invasion. He accused the U.S. and its allies of ignoring Russia’s demands to prevent Ukraine from joining NATO and for security guarantees. He also claimed that Russia does not intend to occupy Ukraine but will move to “demilitarize” it and bring those who committed crimes to justice.</p>
<p>The attacks came first from the air, but later Ukrainian border guards released security camera footage Thursday showing a line of Russian military vehicles crossing into Ukraine’s government-held territory from Russian-annexed Crimea.</p>
<p>Oleksii Arestovich, an adviser to Zelenskyy, said that Russian troops have moved up to 5 kilometers (3 miles) into the Ukrainian territory in the Kharkiv and Chernihiv regions, and, possibly in other areas.</p>
<p>President Joe Biden pledged new sanctions to punish Russia for the aggression that the international community had expected for weeks but could not prevent through diplomacy.</p>
<p>Putin justified it all in a televised address, asserting that the attack was needed to protect civilians in eastern Ukraine — a false claim the U.S. had predicted he would make as a pretext for an invasion. He accused the U.S. and its allies of ignoring Russia’s demands to prevent Ukraine from joining NATO and for security guarantees. He also claimed that Russia does not intend to occupy Ukraine but will move to “demilitarize” it and bring those who committed crimes to justice.</p>
<p>Biden in a written statement condemned the “unprovoked and unjustified attack,” and he promised that the U.S. and its allies would “hold Russia accountable.” The president said he planned to speak to Americans on Thursday after a meeting of the Group of Seven leaders. More sanctions against Russia were expected to be announced Thursday.</p>
<p>Ukraine’s Foreign Minister Dmytro Kuleba described the assault as a “full-scale invasion” and said Ukraine will “defend itself and will win. The world can and must stop Putin. The time to act is now.”</p>
<p>In the capital, Kyiv Mayor Vitaly Klitschko advised residents to stay home unless they are involved in critical work and urged them to prepare go-bags with necessities and documents if they need to evacuate. An Associated Press photographer in Mariupol reported hearing explosions and seeing dozens of people with suitcases heading for their cars to leave the city.</p>
<p>“We are facing a war and horror. What could be worse?” 64-year-old Liudmila Gireyeva said in Kyiv. She planned to head to the western city of Lviv and then to try to move to Poland to join her daughter. Putin “will be damned by history, and Ukrainians are damning him.”</p>
<p>The Russian claims about knocking out Ukrainian air defenses and Ukrainian claims to have shot down several Russian aircraft could not immediately be verified. The Ukrainian air defense system and air force date back to the Soviet era and are dwarfed by Russia’s massive air power and its inventory of precision weapons.</p>
<p>The Russian Defense Ministry said it was not targeting cities, but using precision weapons and claimed that “there is no threat to civilian population.”</p>
<p>Zelenskyy urged global leaders to provide defense assistance to Ukraine and help protect its airspace from the “aggressor.” The European Union Aviation Safety Agency told air operators of a high risk to civilian aircraft over Ukraine, reminding air operators that “this is now an active conflict zone.”</p>
<p>Anton Gerashchenko, an adviser to Ukraine’s interior minister, said on Facebook that the Russian military had launched missile strikes on Ukrainian military command facilities, air bases and military depots in Kyiv, Kharkiv and Dnipro.</p>
<p>After the initial explosions in Kyiv, people could be heard shouting in the streets. Then a sense of normality returned, with cars circulating and people walking in the streets as a pre-dawn commute appeared to start in relative calm.</p>
<p>The consequences of the conflict and resulting sanctions on Russia started reverberating throughout the world.</p>
<p>World stock markets plunged and oil prices surged by nearly $6 per barrel. Market benchmarks tumbled in Europe and Asia and U.S. futures were sharply lower. Brent crude oil jumped to over $100 per barrel Thursday on unease about possible disruption of Russian supplies. The ruble sank</p>
<p>Anticipating international condemnation and countermeasures, Putin issued a stark warning to other countries not to meddle, saying, “whoever tries to impede us, let alone create threats for our country and its people, must know that the Russian response will be immediate and lead to the consequences you have never seen in history.”</p>
<p>In a stark reminder of Russia’s nuclear power, Putin warned that “no one should have any doubts that a direct attack on our country will lead to the destruction and horrible consequences for any potential aggressor.”</p>
<p>Though the U.S. on Tuesday announced the repositioning of forces around the Baltics, Biden has said he will not send in troops to fight Russia.</p>
<p>Putin’s announcement came just hours after the Ukrainian president rejected Moscow’s claims that his country poses a threat to Russia and made a passionate, last-minute plea for peace.</p>
<p>“The people of Ukraine and the government of Ukraine want peace,” Zelenskyy said in an emotional overnight address, speaking in Russian in a direct appeal to Russian citizens. “But if we come under attack, if we face an attempt to take away our country, our freedom, our lives and lives of our children, we will defend ourselves. When you attack us, you will see our faces, not our backs.”</p>
<p>Zelenskyy said he asked to arrange a call with Putin late Wednesday, but the Kremlin did not respond.</p>
<p>In an apparent reference to Putin’s move to authorize the deployment of the Russian military to “maintain peace” in eastern Ukraine, Zelensky warned that “this step could mark the start of a big war on the European continent.”</p>
<p>“Any provocation, any spark could trigger a blaze that will destroy everything,” he said.</p>
<p>He challenged the Russian propaganda claims, saying that “you are told that this blaze will bring freedom to the people of Ukraine, but the Ukrainian people are free.”</p>
<p>At an emergency meeting of the U.N. Security Council called by Ukraine because of the imminent threat of a Russian invasion, members still unaware of Putin’s announcement appealed to him to stop an attack. U.N. Secretary-General Antonio Guterres opened the meeting, just before the announcement, telling Putin: “Give peace a chance.”</p>
<p>European Council President Charles Michel and European Commission President Ursula von der Leyen promised to hold the Kremlin accountable.</p>
<p>“In these dark hours, our thoughts are with Ukraine and the innocent women, men and children as they face this unprovoked attack and fear for their lives,” they said on Twitter.</p>
<p>Even before Putin’s announcement, dozens of nations imposed sanctions on Russia, further squeezing Russian oligarchs and banks out of international markets.</p>
<p>The Russian Foreign Ministry has shrugged off the sanctions, saying that “Russia has proven that, with all the costs of the sanctions, it is able to minimize the damage.”</p>
<p>The threat of war has already shredded Ukraine’s economy and raised the specter of massive casualties, energy shortages across Europe and global economic chaos.</p>
<!--EndFragment-->]]>
    </content>
    <link href="/blog/biden-was-right-warmongering-putin-starts-new-world-war-and-republicans-cheer-him-on/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <published>2022-03-13T19:29:01+01:00</published>
    <updated>2022-03-13T19:29:01+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:lang="en">
    <id>/about/</id>
    <title>About</title>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>A ready to use static blog, powered by <a href="https://cecil.app">Cecil</a>.</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="how-to-use">How to use?</h2>
<h3 id="managing-content-with-forestry-https-forestry-io">Managing content with <a href="https://forestry.io">Forestry</a></h3>
<p>If your goal is managing content quickly, and decide later where to deploy to it, use the following button to import the starter blog to Forestry CMS and start editing immediatelly!</p>
<p><a href="https://cecil.app/cms/forestry/import/"><img src="https://assets.forestry.io/import-to-forestryK.svg" alt="Import this project into Forestry" /></a></p>
<h3 id="deploy-with-netlify-https-www-netlify-com">Deploy with <a href="https://www.netlify.com">Netlify</a></h3>
<p>Otherwise, if your goal is deploying a new blog quickly, and manage content mannually, use the following button to configure and deploy your new blog on Netlify.</p>
<p><a href="https://app.netlify.com/start/deploy?repository=https://github.com/Cecilapp/the-butler&amp;stack=cms"><img src="https://www.netlify.com/img/deploy/button.svg" alt="Deploy to Netlify" /></a></p>]]>
    </content>
    <link href="/about/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <published>2019-07-09T02:00:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2019-07-09T02:00:00+02:00</updated>
  </entry>
</feed>
